Thank you very much. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Himbrich is a peaceful city and the people here are just lovely. I think we're secure here.
Himbrich is very calm and is all I can. It's lovely, it's very peaceful.
Him from all over the world come here to learn English also to do degrees.
There are a lot of English students because of Cambridge University but also a lot of international students.
So there is quite a good life for young people.
My name is Cristina. I'm from Belgium and I'm 18 years old so I just finished high school in June.
I was quite confused about what I wanted to study this year. So I decided to do one year program, which is the foundation program.
But also to improve my English because when I came here it was not that good.
My name is Michaela Shbert. I'm from Czech Republic. I spent here a year affecting my English and to be honest really figuring out what I want to do with my life.
And then I met my English boyfriend, decided to really stay and do all the things I wanted to do here.
I started the university, I wanted to do what I wanted to do. So I'm sending a film and media here in Cambridge.
My name is Carolina Blay and I'm from Venezuela and basically I'm doing a foundation course and it's to study here in the UK.
My parents told me I would like to go to a different country and learn English.
I said, yeah, why not? They told me, why don't you go to Canada or America because it's quite near to Venezuela and I say, I would like to go to England.
Really? Yeah, I would like to go to Cambridge and I don't know why it was like a feeling I wanted to go there.
Then when we were like to sign if it was better to stay in a home stay or in a residence, I say, I think I would like to stay in a home stay.
So I go practice with my house mom and my house dad and meet a really real family and how they live and everything.
I think I made the right choice.
My name is Sylvia and I'm from Italy and we are in Cambridge now in I'm a home stay girl.
And here in this house is my first time but I went to Cambridge twice a year ago for the same reason starting at school and home stay.
Yes, it's my first time.
And it's so cool.
And it means now that they give us everything for the accommodation, laundry, everything and the conversation that is the most important part of our, of this own stay.
And it's very nice.
I mean it's the right thing to do to learn language for me.
Well, home stay is basically a language in coming to live with a British family.
Be integrated into the family and immerse themselves in English to help them learn.
The basic home stay booking would be on a half board basis which is bed breakfast and evening meal.
And the student would expect obviously their own room and less specified in which case they make share with a friend in a twin room basis.
But they would expect obviously a bed wardrobe, a desk, lighting so much work.
Other extras may be into the access by Wi-Fi.
They would have access to laundry facilities and cooking facilities if they are booking on a self-catering basis.
Well, in my home stay, I have dinner with them every day at six.
And also with a different students that are in the house as well.
And every Thursday they wash my clothes and they clean my room.
And actually because I've been in my home stay for a year and a half.
I play a squash with my house mom every Sunday and we enjoy different activities together.
I've been in the birthday of the kids and everything.
No, I'm really a member of the family.
Well, home stay is where you stay with an English family.
And when I send English family encompasses all different nationalities of become part of English life.
And then you usually spend the morning at school at the afternoon free.
And then in the evening there's always a meal ready for you.
And we all sit at the table, talk about what you've done during the day.
Perhaps discuss different aspects of English life.
Hello, I would like to dig my eyes.
I don't know when are the next available these?
Oh, okay, that's no problem.
Here's a list of the next available pilot states in Cambridge.
For example, I think the next one is April.
I knew actually people who came here before to do the same program as me.
And one of them told me about her home stay.
That was really good and she enjoyed a lot.
So she recommended to me and the best school also recommended us some good home stays.
And so I chose to go in the one I'm here now because I knew how it would happen more or less.
And also because we had a kitchen for the students.
We had quite good things in this specific family.
Often I understand the students have known previous students who've been in our house.
And so they apparently when they send an application in or first met in a garage at the Bell School,
they say it does, this is going to have a room.
And then the Bell School would phone me and ask if I have a room for giving the dates.
And it goes from there.
When you say can you tell the judge that you are not going to eat home tonight?
Because I booked in Canada for your birthday.
My home mother she cooks every day.
And in the beginning I was a little afraid because of the stereotypes of English food.
But that's really not true because I am lucky.
I expect that bad food is what I have food for.
Thank you very much.
I think it's that immersing themselves in English.
Being in a British family, speaking English all the time.
It's completely different to learning it in a classroom and perhaps speaking with somebody else who is also learning it.
And you know you're picking up that native language basically.
At school you learn grammar, make exercise of listening comprehension so on.
But then these things you have to practice and the family is the way you can practice language.
You can learn when you get wrong.
They can correct your mistakes and so on.
Yes, I think if you stand a student dormitory.
You're more likely to meet people of the same nationality and not practice your English as well as it would if you were a home-stay.
When you're in a home-stay you have to speak English.
As a school I'm really learning the grammar vocabulary, the English language.
But in my host family I have the chance to speak with them and to practice the English accent.
And I think by hearing them always speaking at the inner time that helps me a lot to see how to speak.
I think by hearing a lot I learn also.
Often their accent needs encouragement and help.
They encourage to listen a little bit so they can match our speech patterns for intonation.
And this happens very much in the dining room over across the table.
And the fact that my husband was a professor of linguistics he can always give the reasons.
Sometimes I think the explanations are a little bit about the students, but it's a delightly, some must go in.
It was a whole family, mom, dad, and they had two kids.
And I found it quite helpful that the children didn't speak such a complicated language.
And they had many tools to learn to write and read because they go to school here very early, the age of five, I believe.
So always when I didn't know something they would draw me a picture of it and try to explain me.
So once you get the word this way, you will never forget it because you have the whole interaction and whole experience wrapped around it.
Yes, so that was brilliant.
I believe that it's doing these simple things with them, like to eat, to watch TV.
You don't talk to me, so you don't need to use that too much language because you are just a beginner.
But even though if you don't realize it, but it all has the fact that you sleep on it, and next day you feel something got in.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
I would advise if you're looking for home stay, please tell the company the school as much information as possible what you're looking for.
So then the service, we have to place you into a house family.
If you tell that you want internet, you're allergic to certain animals, we need to know as much information as possible, so to make your experience perfect.
Try to interact with them and be part of the family.
Sometimes you have to also think that you are not in your country anymore, and you have to adapt to some situations.
It's not going to be the same for your home or your home or back in your country.
It's not going to be, you know, almost everything is going to be different.
So maybe you have to give a little bit about you and try to adapt to different situations and enjoy the time of course.
Just not to be scared because the family know how to deal with you, how to make you comfortable and so on.
So there's no problem because they know how to to make you to feel you at home.
There are two things which I would be the worst and you need to find a balance in between.
The worst thing is to be too shy.
And the other thing is to be too arrogant.
Nothing will get you anywhere.
So you need to find the balance somewhere in between and find your confidence.
And take the dictionary if you have it always in your pocket.
Whatever you see in front of you, try to interact with the people.
And live it.
Don't come here, don't bring your world with you here and don't continue living in your culture and everything.
You need to open for it and then it all comes to you and it will find it easier and easier to learn the language.
It's going to be a great experience not only in terms of learning English but in learning about life.
Because you will encounter many different views of life.
Very many different styles amongst the student that you hadn't realized what exists before.
So you don't only come to learn English.
You come to learn about how people live in the rest of the world.
Thank you very much.