Hi Bob the Canadian here. Let's learn English around the house. Come on in.
Hi Bob the Canadian here. Welcome to this video. If this is your first time here, don't forget
to click the subscribe button below and give me a thumbs up at some point during this video
if it's helping you learn English. Well today we're going to learn some English words and phrases
that you can use to describe a house. I just came in through the front door.
Houses generally have a front door and a back door. I'll show you that one a bit later. And I'm
standing in the front entrance or the entrance way of the house. It's a little warm so I'm going to
take off my coat and you'll notice behind me there's a coat hanger. So I'm going to hang my coat
here and I'm going to do what we traditionally do in Canada and that is that I'm going to take off my shoes.
Before we go any further though, I want to thank Barb the Canadian for letting me use her
house today to make this video to help you learn English. The front entrance way also usually has
a closet where you can hang coats and other items. So especially in the winter when you come into
a home you might want to hang your coat in the closet if there's not enough room on the coat hangers.
So you'll notice behind me here the kitchen. The kitchen is one of my favorite rooms in the house.
I really like food so I really like kitchens. You'll notice behind me here that a kitchen has a
certain number of items we have the refrigerator or the fridge where you can keep food cold. This
fridge has a freezer on the bottom. We also have the stove and generally we call this part
the oven where you would bake things. And here we have the stove where you would cook things.
If you look behind me here you'll see we have a sink. So when you're all done, making your food and
eating your food you can do the dishes. You can wash the dishes in the sink. And if you look over here
on the counter you'll notice that we have three things that you find quite often in a kitchen.
We have a coffee maker. We have a kettle for boiling water and we have a pitcher of water if you
just want to drink some water. Up here you'll notice that we have cupboards. So cupboards notice
it's not pronounced the way it looks. In a cupboard you'll find things like plates and bowls
that you can use for eating. Those are pretty loud. And if we look over here we'll have what we
in Canada would call a utensil drawer. So this is a drawer where you would keep spoons for and knives.
You'll also see this area here is what we would call the counter or the counter top. You can use
both words interchangeably. So you might use the counter top or the counter to prepare food.
And you'll notice hiding over here in the corner we have a microwave just a small appliance
that lets you heat up food really, really quickly. So that's the kitchen. One of my favorite rooms.
Let's move on to the living room. So we're in the living room now. The living room is the room in the
home where you will usually find chairs and sofas or what we also call couches. It's the room where
when you just want to relax. This is the room that you would generally sit in. Maybe you want to read a
book. Maybe you want to watch TV. If we look over here you'll see that this living room also has a TV
a television where you could sit just to have a quiet relaxing evening where you are going to
entertain yourself by reading a book. Maybe sitting and talking with friends or watching some television.
So that's a living room. Let's look at the dining room next. Another part of the house that I really
like is the dining room. So this is a room with a table specifically for eating meals. So you would have
breakfast, lunch and supper at this table in the dining room. You can tell that Christmas is coming soon.
I'll do a video soon about Christmas. I think next week I'm going to a parade and I'll show you
a whole bunch of stuff about Christmas. But this is the dining room. We have a dining room table and we have
chairs to sit at as we would eat our meals. So we're in the bathroom now and there's really
three main parts to a bathroom. We have a sink where you could wash your hands so you could turn
on the water and wash your hands. We also have if I turn just a little bit behind me here we have
shower so you could jump in here to have a shower. Maybe at the end of a long day of work.
And then we also have and I'm not going to describe what this is for. But we also have a toilet.
I think everyone in the world knows what this is for and how to use it. So I'm not going to spend
any time describing it but you have a toilet. This is the toilet seat. You have toilet paper.
And this is where you would go. If you felt the call of nature, that's the nice way of putting it.
So we're in the upstairs of the house now. You'll notice that we're in a bedroom. So there's a
good reason why it's called a bedroom. It's because there's a bed. So in a bedroom you're going to
have a bed. Here also going to have things that in English we call dressers. So if you look over here
there is a dresser and a dresser is a place where using these drawers. This is where you would
store all of your clothes. So in a bedroom you generally have a bed just right here and you have
a dresser where you can store stuff. There's also in this bedroom what we would call night tables.
So there's a table on each side of the bed with a small lamp. This is a place where you could keep a
book if you read at night before you go to bed. You would keep it on your night stand or night
table. So this is a bedroom. I'm not sure how easy this is to see but I'm standing in a hallway.
So a hallway is the part of the home that connects all the rooms together. This room is empty.
In English we would call this a spare room. Sometimes a spare room has an extra bed in it. This
room is just empty. So we would call this a spare room. I just came down these stairs and I'm now
in the basement of this house. A basement is the part of the house that is below ground and many
times in a home the basement is used to store things. It also usually has a furnace. This is what
heats the home with gas or oil in the winter and a hot water heater. This is what makes hot water
for the house as well. And usually those types of things are found in a basement. So we're here in the
basement. It's the part that's below ground. I'll just show you a window over here for a sec so that you
get a sense of where we are. So here's the basement window. It's a little hard to see. But if you look
outside you'll notice that we are at ground level or below ground level in the basement here.
So a lot of Canadian homes will also have a garage. A garage is a place where you can keep your car
and a garage has a garage door which you just saw open behind me as well. A garage sometimes has
a garage door opener. This is a device that's on the ceiling of the garage. I'll just show you
for a sec. This is a device that's on the ceiling of a garage that opens the door automatically
when you click the button in your car. So that's a garage door opener. It's a little cold to be out
here with no coat on but I just wanted to show you earlier I mentioned the back door. This is the
back door of the house. When you have a back door a lot of times you'll have a barbecue outside
and then also down here there's just kind of a patio area. So there's an area where you can come out
to cook some food in the summer months when it's warmer. You can come out your back door. You can
go down your steps and you can use your barbecue to cook some food. So this is a small patio area
outside the back door. Well hey thanks for joining me today to learn some English that you can use
around a house. Bob the Canadian here. Learn English with Bob the Canadian. If you haven't yet
please click the subscribe button below and the small bell icon so that you can be notified of new
videos. Give me a thumbs up if you like this video and it helped you learn English and please do
share this video with a friend or anyone you know that is learning English. Don't forget as well
to scroll down. There is some bonus material in the description below to help you practice some of
the English that you have learned in this video. Bob the Canadian here. Learn English with Bob
the Canadian. I hope you enjoyed this video and have a great day.